[
  {
    "type": "instructions",
    "note": "Each question is followed by four options lettered A to D. Find the correct option for each question"
  },
  {
    "type": "quiz",
    "no": "1",
    "question": "The instrument used to measure relative humidity is the ",
    "answer": "A",
    "options": {
      "A": "hydrometer.",
      "B": "hygrometer.",
      "C": "rain gauge.",
      "D": "wind vane."
    }
  },
  {
    "type": "quiz",
    "no": "3",
    "question": "The light travels from glass to air, its speed ",
    "answer": "A",
    "options": {
      "A": "increased.",
      "B": "reduced.",
      "C": "halved",
      "D": "unchange."
    }
  },{
    "type": "quiz",
    "no": "4",
    "question": "When a piece of iron is brought near a permanent magnet for a while, it becomes magnetized by",
    "answer": "D",
    "options": {
      "A": "stroking method.",
      "B": "electrical method.",
      "C": "friction.",
      "D": "induction."
    }
  },
  {
    "type": "quiz",
    "no": "5",
    "question": "A rhestat is used in an electric circuit in order to ",
    "answer": "C",
    "options": {
      "A": "increase electric current only.",
      "B": "decrease electric current only.",
      "C": "keep electric current constant.",
      "D": "Increase and decrease electric current."
    }
  },
  {
    "type": "quiz",
    "no": "6",
    "question": "Which of the following about an opaque object is correct? An opaque object ",
    "answer": "C",
    "options": {
      "A": "allows light to pass through it partially.",
      "B": "allows light to pass through fully.",
      "C": "forms a shadow",
      "D": "does not form a shadow"
    }
  },
  {
    "type": "quiz",
    "no": "7",
    "question": "One of the characteristics of a solid is that ",
    "answer": "B",
    "options": {
      "A": "Its particles are tightly packed.",
      "B": "It assumes the shape of the container it occupies.",
      "C": "It has no fixed volume.",
      "D": "Its particles can easily be seperated."
    }
  },
  {
    "type": "quiz",
    "no": "8",
    "question": "The instrument used to measure current in an electric circuit is the ",
    "answer": "D",
    "options": {
      "A": "ammeter.",
      "B": "photometer.",
      "C": "thermometer.",
      "D": "voltmeter."
    }
  },{
    "type": "quiz",
    "no": "9",
    "question": "The bottom of a pool of water appears closer to the surface than it is. Which of the following properties accounts for this? ",
    "answer": "C",
    "options": {
      "A": "reflection.",
      "B": "transparency of water.",
      "C": "refraction.",
      "D": "rectilinear propagation of light."
    }
  },
  {
    "type": "quiz",
    "no": "10",
    "question": "An example of a source of energy which is non-renewable is?",
    "answer": "A",
    "options": {
      "A": "petroleum.",
      "B": "solar",
      "C": "tide.",
      "D": "wind."
    }
  },
  {
    "type": "quiz",
    "no": "12",
    "question": "The number of oxygen atoms present in three molecules of carbon dioxide is",
    "answer": "C",
    "options": {
      "A": "3.",
      "B": "4.",
      "C": "5.",
      "D": "6."
    }

  }
]
